

Porto Belo, Brazil

**** +55 48 999290820

Profile

Software Engineer with more than a decade of experience in creating and maintaining systems. He has been working with Ruby on Rails for seven years and React for four years.

Focused on solving problems, producing tested, refactored, clean and effective source code. Dedicated to the development process, it does not dispense with the use of agile methodologies.

Able to self-manage effectively during projects, as well as collaborate as part of a team.

Current work stack:

Ruby on Rails, Nodejs, Postgres, MongoDB, Redis, RabbitMQ

Employment History

Software Engineer, Asseinfo, Tijucas

June 2009 — June 2022

12+ years of ERP (inventory, finance, billing, production) systems experience.

Ruby on Rails backend since 2015 and React frontend since 2019.

Building back-end services and APIs to support new and existing product initiatives.

Building tests with RSpec, Jest, Cypress.

Analysis and development of new features, as well as revamp existing features.

Mentoring new team members and participating in a multidisciplinary and self-managing team.

Backend developer, Meta, São Paulo

July 2022

Working as a software developer for Brazilian clients.

Allocated at Youse Seguros | Practice areas: Insurance policies.

Building back-end microservices and Rest APIs to support new and existing product initiatives.

Building test with RSpec.

Analysis and development of new features, as well as revamp existing features.

Participating in a multidisciplinary and self-managing team.

In the team's day-to-day we use concepts from XP, Scrum, Kanban, Agile.

Backend developer, Consulta Remédios, Curitiba

November 2022 — August 2023

Working in a medicine marketplace.

The marketplace is composed of some applications with separate concepts. They communicate via REST API.

Details

Nationality

Brazilian

Links

LinkedIn

Github

Skills

SQL

HTML & CSS

MongoDB

Node.js

MySQL

React

Docker

Git

JavaScript

Ruby on Rails

Agile Methodologies

PostgreSQL

Kanban

SOLID

Design Patterns

Languages

English

Hobbies

Play video games, read comics, study new technologies, travel and discover new places.

The source code is legacy so on a daily basis there is a lot of code refactoring and also many existing bug fixes.

Current work stack: Ruby on Rails, Postgres, MongoDB, Redis, RabbitMQ, Sidekiq

Software Engineer, InDebtet

August 2023

As a Software Engineer at InDebted, I work on some products to support our customers in their journey to be debt free.

- Keeping and developing the payment portal to support the customer's payment journey.
- Keeping and developing integrations to support onboarding new customers and clients.

Stack: Event sourcing, micro-services (lambdas), Go, React, Docker, AWS, Buildkite, Stripe

Education

Bachelor of Computer Science, Univali, Itajaí

March 2000 — July 2008

Courses

RubyConf Brasil 2021, Locaweb

July 2021

React Conf Brasil 2020

November 2020

Agile Brazil 2014, Agile Aliance

November 2014